Guide to the Coca-Cola Company Star Salesman Kit, 1949-1951
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Coca-Cola Company Star Salesman Kit 1949-1951
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Coca-Cola Company
2 linear feet Extent: 43 Items
The Coca-Cola Company was founded in Atlanta in 1886 by John Pemberton. The Star Salesman Kit was part of a program developed to train Coca-Cola salesmen. The Coca-Cola Company Star Salesman Kit dates from 1949-1951 and consists of numbered training lessons, memorabilia buttons, 35mm filmstrips and accompanying phonograph records, which together comprise a training program for Coca-Cola sales employees. Topics covered include increasing sales, product placement, stock magazines, coolers and vending machines, and selling to women. Acquired as a part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
RL.00238
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, original audiovisual materials are closed to research until use copies can be produced. Contact Research Services for more information.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Coca-Cola Company Star Salesman Kit was purchased by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 2010.
Historical Note
For information on the history of the Coca-Cola Company, visit the corporate website:
thecoca-colacompany.com
Collection Overview
The Coca-Cola Company Star Salesman Kit dates from 1949-1951 and consists of numbered training lessons, memorabilia buttons, 35mm filmstrips and accompanying phonograph records, which together comprise a training program for Coca-Cola sales employees. Topics covered include increasing sales, product placement, stock magazines, coolers and vending machines, and selling to women.
Collection Arrangement
Items were removed from the Salesman Kit case and arranged by format: printed materials, filmstrips, and phonograph records.
Subject Headings
Coca-Cola Company; Coca-Cola Company -- Employees -- Training of; Sales force management; Sales management -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Sales management -- Handbooks, manuals, etc. -- United States; Sales promotion -- United States; Sales Personnel -- Training of -- United States; Sales Personnel -- Training of -- United Sates -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Sales personnel -- Training of; Sales personnel -- United States; Selling -- Instructional materials; Selling -- Instructional materials -- United States; Selling -- Programmed instruction; Selling -- United States; Women consumers; 35mm; Phonograph records; Filmstrips; The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center Collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Albert B. Stridsberg Papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. New York Office. Research Department Records
Bill Communications Sales and Marketing Management Vertical Files
Garrett Orr Papers
John Benjamin Harris Papers
Roy Lightner Collection Of Antique Advertisements
Contents of Collection
- Star Salesman Kit, 1949-1951, (4 boxes)
  Restrictions on Access: Original audiovisual materials are closed to researchers until use copies can be produced. Contact Research Services staff for more information.
  - Case (Box 1)
  - Star Salesman Kit case, 1950 (Box 1)
    [The kit case is made of wood, green in color. Inside the case, one side holds print materials folders and meeting notes, and the other side holds filmstrips and phonograph records. The case measures 24x19x5.5 inches.]
  - Training Folders (Box 2)
    [Folder titles correspond with 35mm filmstrips and phonograph records. Parts Six and Eight are missing and are also missing in filmstrips and phonograph records.]
    - Coin cooler manual, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Part One, Here's How, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
      [Suggestion Illustravox buyers guide included in folder.]
    - Part Two, It's Got to Be Sold, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Part Three, What's in it?, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Part Four, Under Cover Man, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Part Five, A Matter of Degrees, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Part Seven, The Woman in Your Life, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Part Nine, The Sellingest Man in Town, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Profit meter field test report, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
  - Button pins, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    [Inscribed with the title of Part Three folder; What's in It? and picture of kangaroo, also featured on folder.]
  - 35mm Filmstrips (Box 3)
    [Some items do not have corresponding printed material, but correspond with phonographic records. Arranged alphabetically.]
    - A Route Manager Works With Plant Management, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - A Route Manager Works With the Route Salesmen, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - A Route Manager Works With the Routes, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Are You This Man?, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Leadership, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part One, Here's How, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part Two, It's Got to Be Sold, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part Three, What's in it?, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part Four, Under Cover Man, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part Five, A Matter of Degrees, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part Seven, The Woman in Your Life, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Part Nine, The Sellingest Man in Town, 1949-1950 (Box 3)
    - Partners for Profit, 1951 (Box 3)
  - Phonograph Records (Box 4)
    Arranged alphabetically.
    - A Route Manager Works With Plant Management, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - A Route to Manager Works With the Route Salesmen, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - A Route Manager Works With the Routes, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Are You This Man?, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Get Out and Under, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Leadership, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part One, Here's How, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part Two, It's Got to Be Sold, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part Three, What's in it?, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part Four, Under Cover Man, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part Five, A Matter of Degrees, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part Seven, The Woman in Your Life, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Part Nine, The Sellingest Man in Town, 1949-1950 (Box 4)
    - Partners for Profit, 1951 (Box 4)